# Chad Gooch

Indianapolis, Indiana, United States



chad.t.gooch88@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/chad-gooch-1525b8a2

### Summary

Having been a system administrator and network infrastructure engineer, I am growing my career in the IT field. Computers have been part of my daily life for over 20 years and I have learned a great deal about issues that arise and how to fix and prevent these issues. I excel at understanding and troubleshooting computers, electronics and networks and I am currently working as a system administrator building more experience.

### **Experience**



## System Administrator

Hydro-Gear

Feb 2018 - Jul 2021 (3 years 6 months)

Project Management, ADDS(account creation, group membership, group creation, and password resets), Exchange 2010, Exchange 2016, Exchange Migrations and encryption, Azure AD sync, basic to advanced Network troubleshooting of OSI model(including NAT and PAT) as well as VLANs, Serial Communication and COM port configuration, Cat5e and Cat6 cable troubleshooting and repair, Domain Management, Citrix, SCCM, Maintain Documentation, Printer and Print Server Management, end user support, Microsoft Office installations and management including Outlook, Visio and Project, Domain Functional level updates, DHCP configuration(including reservations), DNS configuration, Group Policy(GPO) update and management, Server deployment and configuration, basic scripting in visual basic(vbs) and powershell, Door Access control systems, security camera systems, computer security settings(domain registered anti-virus as well as GPO control), network shares, backup systems, Nutanix hardware setup and control, as well as Hyper-V.

### **System Administrator**

Sumco Group, LLC

Aug 2015 - Feb 2018 (2 years 7 months)

System Administrator, Network Administrator, and Help desk all in one.

Swing Migrations, Project Management, GPO's, DNS, DHCP, Firewalls, IIS, ADDS, Exchange, Networking, Camera Systems, Domain Management, Purchasing Decisions, Print Management, and end user support. Microsoft Office 2010 installations and management including Outlook, Visio and Project.

### **Help Desk**

Bell Techlogix, Inc.

Nov 2014 - Apr 2015 (6 months)

Provide tier 1-3 support for 7 different companies.

Troubleshooting users computers including hardware and networking.

Maintain accurate tickets.

Virus removal and prevention, Software installation and configuration.

### **Education**

# TechSkills-Indianapolis

Certificate of Completion, Network and System Administration/Administrator 2014 - 2015

Advanced knowledge and Certification of computer systems and networks.

Disassemble, repair, and assembly of infrastructure equipment including computers.

Advanced networking and configuration of infrastructure equipment.

# Naval Nuclear Power Training Command

Engineer's Degree, Nuclear/Nuclear Power Technology/Technician 1999 - 2001

Nuclear Technology with emphasis on Electronics and Electrical and Mechanical Systems.

Thermodynamics, Processes, Materials, Chemicals, Circuit boards, etc.

Principles of current flow (both conventional and electron).

Composition and principles of electronics including but not limited to logic gates.

### **Licenses & Certifications**

COMPTIA A+ - CompTIA

Issued Aug 2014 - Expires Aug 2017 T7P84SDL8C1Q141X

**MTA Network Fundamentals** - Microsoft

E952-5268

#### CompTIA Network + - CompTIA

**MTA Server Administration Fundamentals 98-365** - Microsoft

F134-3389

**MTA Windows Operating System Fundamentals 98-349** - Microsoft

F068-3590

98-367 MTA security fundamentals - Microsoft

F209-8639

### CompTIA Security+ - CompTIA

Issued Jul 2021 - Expires Jul 2024

### **Skills**

Computers • Electronics • Networking • Customer Service • Windows • Computer Hardware • Word Processing • Troubleshooting • Work Well Independently • Efficiency